## SAVIOUR IMODE PHONE: 07436415716

EMAIL: saviour.imode@gmail.com

# **PROFILE**

Motivated, detail and teamwork-oriented professional with irreproachable experience and wideranging knowledge, with a strong background in relational database management, reporting, business intelligence, Office Management, Office Operations, Customer Service, and communications field. Energetic & hardworking, with a strong sense of learning and self-development. Strategic-relationship and partnership-building skills, creatively. I have held various roles in hands-on and hands-off analytical positions, utilizing Microsoft SQL Server, power Bi, SSIS and Excel.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

Microsoft SQL Server 2012,2019, SSIS, T-SQL Querying, Excel Graphs, Charts, Formula, Calculations, What-if analysis, Goal Seek, Pivot table, VLOOKUP, Customer facing Project, Excellent analytical skills (listening, questioning, challenging, modeling, etc.), Pragmatic problem-solver, PowerPoint, Microsoft Visio, Eras, SPSS and Outlook.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# CYGNET HEALTH CARE BI DEVELOPER

**AUGUST 2021 – TILL DATE** 

- o Work with other members of the Analytics team to identify and deliver reporting solutions to address business challenges.
- o Debugging and troubleshooting of existing reports.

### **HORIZON FRAME**

#### **BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE DEVELOPER**

**MAY 2018 – AUGUST 2021** 

- o Worked on different databases and systems to acquire the required information.
- o I delivered actionable insight by performing analytics to measure, interpret and predict business trends.
- Developed, deployed and maintained BI interfaces including query tools, data visualisation, interactive dashboards/reports, data modelling tools.
- o Ensured consistency of Company style and content is used throughout reports.
- Design and built lists, crosstabs, graphs, scorecards, metrics, filters, prompts, standard reports, and dashboards.
- Created dimensional data models to support business metrics and analytics, with flexibility for change.
- Design and development of high-quality dashboards / reports using tools like Power BI, SSIS,
  Excel/PowerPivot. Develop custom reports, analytics and KPI's for the Business.
- I worked closely with Operations team in the production and ad-hoc reports, develop and maintained operational data quality dashboards to highlight potential areas for improvement or further investigation.
- o Built real-time data and reporting solutions.
- o Maintained and improve existing reports, dashboard and other tools developed by the team to better adjust to the evolving needs of the sites.
- o Provided feedback and recommendations related to the different data collection systems.

- o Strong documentation skills to create requirement documentation.
- o Identified opportunities to meet evolving business needs; utilize various technology/applications/ methodologies to rapidly generate impactful visualizations.
- o Develop and deliver presentations /communications to management or broader audiences.
- o Prioritize and manage own workload to deliver quality results and meet assigned timelines.
- o Working collaboratively with team members and end users during the report writing process.
- o Follow established practices, processes, and guidelines.
- Design and build data models on our BI platform to enable self-service BI and data exploration.
- o Prepare technical and non-technical documentation and presentations.
- Participate in strategic user group discussions to define, standardize, and design analytical solutions helping address key business insights and decision making.
- Ability to work independently, meeting deadlines under pressure, with minimal supervision and frequent interruptions.
- o Contribute to the development and documentation of data management standards framework.
- Liaise with team members and/or other stakeholders to determine analytical solutions requirements including understanding inefficiencies in existing business applications and future business needs.
- o Document all development efforts to ensure traceability.
- Work closely with my colleagues and business stakeholders including the Board to analyse requirements, deliver solid solutions and provide clear feedback.
- o Defined and Documented Metric Definitions and Attributes Definitions.
- o Document detailed business requirements including data, security, Dashboards, Visual Insight and Self-Service reporting requirements.
- Tracked, researched and collected necessary information to be provided in response to external Assessment Information Requests (AIR) within legislated deadlines.
- o Understand the business needs and participate in the technical design of the data flows.
- o Participate actively to the knowledge transfer of support tasks.
- o Proactively identify, prioritize, and conduct analysis that drives meaningful change on KPIs, and critical objectives established by the stakeholder.
- o Provide feedback and recommendations related to the different data collection system.
- o Transform data into information and information into insight.

#### **MENZIES AVIATION**

#### **CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE**

**APRIL 2017 – MAY 2018** 

- o Manage large amount of incoming phone calls.
- o Generated sales leads: helping passengers who missed a flight or connection to re-schedule their travel plans and get them to their destination as quickly as possible.
- o Identify and assess customer's needs to achieve satisfaction.
- o Build sustainable relationships and trust with customer accounts through open and interactive communication.
- o Provide accurate, valid and complete information by using the right methods/tools.
- Handle customer complaints, provide appropriate solutions and alternatives within the time limits; follow up to ensure resolution.
- o Respond promptly to customer inquiries and handle and resolve customer complaints.
- Obtain and evaluate all relevant information to handle product and service inquiries.

 Documenting of information into call tracking system and ensure effective communication at all levels.

	Education & Qualifications
2018	BCS Foundation Certificate in Business Analysis
2012 – 2016	Bachelor of science in Psychology (BSc Hons)

# **Hobbies and Interest**

Making Friends, Volunteering, Social Work, Reading and Team Player.

## Reference

Available on request.